Robert Bly Photographs series, Circa 1900s-2007, undated
University of Minnesota Libraries
Robert Bly Photographs series
Circa 1900s-2007, undated
Bly, Robert
University of Minnesota Libraries. Literary Manuscripts Collection, Manuscripts Division. [mss]
2.07 cubic feet (12 flat boxes)
This series, the thirteenth of eighteen, contains both loose photographs and photograph albums beginning with Robert Bly's parents, Jacob and Alice Blys' collections from the 1900s to Robert Bly's childhood and adult photographs in 2007. Many family photographs are included in the series.
Mss 81_s13
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Acquisition
Collection was acquired from the creator in 2006, with additional accruals beginning in 2007.
Arrangement
Robert Bly's career includes many vocations, and the series designations reflect this diversity. Because of his varied career, there is much crossover in the materials of this collection. Researchers are encouraged to review the descriptions of each series carefully.
The files are organized based on what is contained in the majority of the materials for each file. For instance, when most of the items in a particular file contain translated poetry and prose, they are located in the Translations series. When most of the items in a file embody publishing and editing work in translation, they are located in the Publishing and Editing series. Therefore, to study poetry translations as a publishing business venture, researchers are encouraged to review both series.
The collection is organized into eighteen series. Because of the extent of information in the collection, each series is described in a separate finding aid. Please click on the desired series below for a full description of materials contained in it.
To return to the Main finding aid, see: Robert Bly papers (Mss 81)
Biographical Note
For details of Robert Bly's biography, see: Robert Bly papers (Mss 81).
Scope and Content Note
This series includes both loose positive and negative photographs and slides in black and white and color. In addition, photograph albums beginning with Robert Bly's parents, Jacob and Alice (Aws) Blys' collections from the 1900s through Robert Bly's childhood to adult photographs of Bly in 2007 are found in this series. Many family photographs, including the Bly family trip to the Black Hills of South Dakota and Mount Rushmore (under construction) in 1937, as well as the wedding photograph of Robert and Carol Bly in 1955 are contained in the series.
The series is arranged in two subseries to reflect the manner in which the photographs were received in the Archives. Loose photographs were discovered throughout the collection, and separate photograph albums were also received. The photographs in the albums were removed for separate storage, and the albums were retained in the Personal series.
Strict chronology is not found in this series, as many of the photographs were received without dates or other documentation. In addition, the photograph albums were not necessarily created in chronological order.
Related Material
For information about Robert Bly in other collections held at the University of Minnesota Libraries; Manuscripts Division, see: James Wright Papers (Mss 66), and Carol Bly Papers (Mss 79).
In addition, an online presentation of some materials in the Robert Bly papers can be found here: Robert Bly Revealed.
Robert Bly has written copiously to many notable people. For an extensive search of letters written by him, as well as other items in additional collections, researchers may consult the National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the University of Minnesota Libraries. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Bly, Carol; Hall, Donald, 1928-; Ignatow, David, 1914-1997; Tranströmer, Tomas, 1931-; Wright, James Arlington, 1927-1980;; Photographs; Men’s movement
Detailed Contents
The following section contains a detailed list of the materials in the series.
- Series 13. Photographs, Circa 1900s-2007, undated
  This series includes both loose positive and negative photographs and slides in black and white and color. In addition, photograph albums beginning with Robert Bly's parents, Jacob and Alice (Aws) Blys' collections from the 1900s through Robert Bly's childhood to adult photographs of Bly in 2007 are found in this series. Many family photographs, including the Bly family trip to the Black Hills of South Dakota and Mount Rushmore (under construction) in 1937, as well as the wedding photograph of Robert and Carol Bly in 1955 are contained in the series.
  The series is arranged in two subseries to reflect the manner in which the photographs were received in the Archives. Loose photographs were discovered throughout the collection, and separate photograph albums were also received. The photographs in the albums were removed for separate storage, and the albums were retained in the Personal series.
  Strict chronology is not found in this series, as many of the photographs were received without dates or other documentation. In addition, the photograph albums were not necessarily created in chronological order. Every attempt was made to arrange the photographs chronologically.
  - Subseries 1. Loose photographs, Circa 1900, circa 1910s, 1930s, 1944-2007, undated
    - Loose photographs, Circa 1900, Circa 1930s, 1944-1955 (Box Flat Box 02)
    - Loose photographs, 1956-1979 (Box Flat Box 03)
    - Loose photographs, 1980-1986 (Box Flat Box 04)
    - Loose photographs, 1986-1990 (Box Flat Box 05)
    - Loose photographs, 1990-2007 (Box Flat Box 06)
    - Loose slides (non-Robert Bly images), 1967, 1972, circa 1980s-1990s (Box Flat Box 07)
    - Oversize and fragile photographs, Circa 1910s, 1955, circa 1960s, 1992, 2004, undated (Box Flat Box 13)
  - Subseries 2. Album photographs, Circa 1900s-1980s, 2006-2007, undated
    - [Jacob Bly (?) photographs], Circa 1900s-1920s (Box Flat Box 08)
    - [Alice (Aws) Bly (?) photographs], Circa 1900s-1960s (Box Flat Box 08)
    - [Bly extended family (?) photographs], Circa 1900s-1967, undated (Box Flat Box 09)
    - [Jacob Bly keepsake (?) photographs], Circa 1900s-1980s (Box Flat Box 09)
    - [Robert Bly's collection of Jacob Bly photographs (?)], Circa 1900s-1980s (Box Flat Box 09)
    - [Alice Aws (?) photographs], 1912-1946, undated (Box Flat Box 10)
    - Black Hills trip [photographs], 1937 (Box Flat Box 10)
    - [Alice Bly and Carol Bly (?) photographs], Circa 1940, 1962-1972, 1974, undated (Box Flat Box 10)
    - Alice Bly's photographs, 1944-1973, undated (Box Flat Box 11)
    - [Carol Bly (?) photographs], 1948-1972, undated (Box Flat Box 11)
    - [Extended Bly family (?) photographs], Circa 1940s-1980s (Box Flat Box 11)
    - [Men's week photographs], 1987 (?) (Box Flat Box 11)
    - [Robert Bly-Coleman Barks trip to Iran photographs], 2006 (Box Flat Box 12)
    - [80th birthday celebration at Guthrie Theater photographs], 2006-2007 (Box Flat Box 12)